Finding Aid for Hunein F. Maassab papers, 1951-2002
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Hunein F. Maassab papers
1951-2002
Maassab, Hunein F. "John"
0706 Aa 2
Epidemiologist Hunein F. "John" Maassab was a researcher and professor at the University of Michigan School of Public Health. Maassab's papers, 1951-2002, comprise correspondence, publications, and laboratory documents related to his research into cold adapted live virus vaccines for influenza, Respiratory Syncytial Virus (RSV) and other viruses and development of the "flu mist" vaccine. The collection also includes materials for several upper courses Maassab taught in the Department of Epidemiology.
29.5 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The papers were received from Dr. Maassab’s office in the School of Public Health (Donor No. 9366 ) in 2003.
No further additions to the records expected.
The Maassab papers are open for research use with the exception of some files that may contain personally identifiable information on patients or participants in various experiments and trials. These files are closed in accord with applicable law and university policy on patient/client records.
The Maassab papers includes restricted material in the following categories:
Patient/Client Records -- Boxes 15-17, 20, 21, 28-30
Hunein F. "John" Maassab was born in Damascus, Syria in 1928. He emigrated to the United States in 1947, became a permanent resident in 1955, and gained United States citizenship in 1960. He and his wife, Hilda Zahka, had twin sons, Sammy and Fred, born in 1959.
Maassab graduated from Greek Orthodox High School in Damascus in 1945. After moving to the United States, Maassab earned a B.A. in Biology and an M.A. in Physiology and Pharmacology from the University of Missouri. Maassab then moved to the University of Michigan, where he earned his M.Ph. in 1954 and his Ph.D. in Epidemiological Sciences in 1956. Dr. Maassab remained in the Department of Epidemiology in the University of Michigan School of Public Health, where he became a professor in 1960.
Inspired by the work of Dr. Thomas Francis and other pioneers in the Department of Epidemiology, Maassab has dedicated his career to developing cold-adapted live virus vaccines for influenza, Respiratory Syncytial Virus (RSV), and other viruses. This work culminated in the licensing of Maassab's patented "Master Strain" for creating live virus vaccines against Influenza A and B to Aviron, a pharmaceutical company that intended to market the vaccine as "Flu Mist," a nasal-spray alternative to traditional vaccine injections.
The Hunein F. "John" Maassab papers, 1951-2002, consist of correspondence, publications, and laboratory documents related to his research into cold adapted live virus vaccines for influenza, Respiratory Syncytial Virus (RSV) and other viruses and development of the "flu mist" vaccine. The collection also includes materials for several upper courses Maassab taught in the Department of Epidemiology. are divided into six series: General (1967-2002), Teaching (1975-2000), Correspondence (1960-2000), Topical Files (1955-2001), Publications (1954-1999), and Research (1951-1999).
Subjects:
Epidemiology.; Influenza.; Medicine--Michigan.; Public health--United States.; University of Michigan--Faculty.Faculty.; University of Michigan. School of Public Health.
- General, 1967-2002
  General, 1967-2002 comprises primarily biographical and background information about Maassab. It also contains one folder of indexes to reference files. These indexes were originally stored along with the reference materials listed on them in plastic magazine holders in Maassab's office. During processing of the collection, the articles were not retained but the indices were kept as evidence of the extensive reference files.
  - Bibliographies, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - Biographical Sketches, 1984; 1988; 1989; 1993
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1967; 1985; 1990; 1996; 1998 (Box 1)
  - Lists of Abbreviations and Acronyms, undated (Box 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1984-1999 (Box 1)
  - Indexes to References Files, 1982-1993 (Box 1)
  - John Maassab, Public Health Pioneer, 2002; VHS videocassette (Box 1)
- Teaching, 1975-2000
  Teaching, 1975-2000 comprises materials from several courses Maassab taught in the Department of Epidemiology in the University of Michigan's School of Public Health. When it was accessioned, the entire collection had little original order. This was particularly true of the teaching materials, which were stored in letterboxes with no overall organizational scheme or indication of their purpose. As a result, some materials in this series, particularly the figures, notes and overheads at the end of the series, may have originally been used for presentations at professional conferences or other activities other than teaching.
  - Course Materials
    - Epidemiology 519-Introduction to Principles and Methods of Molecular Epidemiology, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
    - Epidemiology 543-Virus Diseases
      - Class Evaluations, 1990; 1992 (Box 1)
      - Class Notes, 1999 (Box 1)
      - Exams, 1976-1996 (Box 1)
      - Handouts
        - Biotechnology, undated (Box 1)
        - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1)
        - Nucleic Acid Transfection, undated (Box 1)
        - Viral Implications, undated (Box 1)
        - Virus Replication, undated (Box 1)
      - Lectures
        - AIDS, undated (Box 1)
        - Definition and Classification of Viruses, undated; 2 folders (Box 1)
        - Emerging Viruses, undated (Box 1)
        - Diagnosis, undated (Box 1)
        - First Lecture, 1998 (Box 1)
        - Genetics, undated; 2 folders (Box 1)
        - Immunization and Anti-Viral Treatments, undated (Box 1)
        - Pathogenesis, undated; 3 folders (Box 2)
        - Persistence, undated (Box 2)
        - Prions, undated (Box 2)
        - Slow Viruses, circa 1993-1998 (Box 2)
        - Transmission, undated (Box 2)
        - Viral Oncogenes, undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
      - Syllabi, 1987-2001 (Box 2)
    - Epidemiology 545-Virus Laboratory Methods
      - Exams and Syllabi, 1980-1995 (Box 2)
      - Lab Experiments and Procedures, undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
      - Lab Practice Manual, undated (Box 2)
    - Epidemiology 547-Tissue Culture Methods, 1977-1980 (Box 2)
    - Epidemiology 548-Methods in Experimental Microbiology, 1975-1987 (Box 2)
    - Epidemiology 560-Mechanisms of Bacterial Pathogenesis, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
    - Epidemiology 570-Immune Mechanisms of Disease, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Epidemiology 594-Genetic Analysis of Cell and Virus Functions, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Epidemiology 624-Vaccinology, 1993-2000 (Box 2)
  - Course Materials (cont.)
    - Epidemiology 680-Hospital Epidemiology, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous Figures, Abstracts and Summaries, undated (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, Images and Charts, undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous Transparencies, undated; 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Thesis Committees (includes a 3.5" floppy disc, WordPerfect files), 1989-2000; 1 floppy disks 3.5" (Box 3)
- Correspondence, 1960-2000
  Correspondence, 1960-2000 is arranged chronologically. When it was accessioned, the papers contained a small series of chronological correspondence files from the 1990s. During processing, these chronological files were retained and expanded to include miscellaneous correspondence that was found dispersed throughout the collection.
  - 1960-1991, 19 folders (Box 3)
  - 1992-2000, 10 folders (Box 4)
- Topical Files, 1955-2001
  Topical Files, 1955-2001 comprises existing background and subject files that were scattered throughout the collection when it was accessioned, along with several files that were created during processing, such as when a significant amount of topically related material was found that did not fit logically into another series. These topical files contain a great deal of correspondence, along with other miscellaneous documents, such as Maassab's graduate school records.
  - 1975 Science Yearbook, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Ackerman Papers, 1957 (Box 4)
  - American Type Culture Collection (ATCC) Deposits, 1980; 1995-1997 (Box 4)
  - Attenuated Live Vaccine (Box 4)
  - Aviron
    - Attenuation Assay Meeting, 1999 (Box 4)
    - Company Prospectus, 1996 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1993-1997; 7 folders (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1998-2001; 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Ferret Study Data, 1995-1998 (Box 5)
    - The Maassab Student Research Award Fund, 1997 (Box 5)
    - Product Licensing Agreement (PLA), 1998 (Box 5)
    - Royalties and Budgets, 1997-1999 (Box 5)
    - Scientific Advisory Board Meeting, 1995 (Box 5)
    - Scientific Advisory Board Meeting, 1997 (Box 5)
    - Supplied Virus Lines, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Baylor-Texas Isolate, 1976-1994 (Box 5)
  - Biological Research Review Committee, 1991-1992 (Box 5)
  - Computer Use Instruction, undated (Box 5)
  - Conferences
    - Cold Spring Harbor, 1996 (Box 5)
    - Consensus Conference on Live Attenuated Influenza Vaccines; Germany, 1998 (Box 5)
    - Influenza Vaccine Workshop; Houston, Texas, 1973 (Box 5)
    - Influenza Workshop V, undated (Box 5)
    - Negative Strand Viruses; Cambridge, Eng, 1985 (Box 5)
    - Presentations, undated (Box 5)
    - Respiratory Infections in Children; France, 1996 (Box 5)
    - Various Conferences, 1986; 1998 (Box 5)
    - Workshop on the Status of Attenuated Influenza Virus; Virginia, 1984 (Box 5)
  - CR 18, 1977-1978 (Box 5)
  - CR 19-CR 22 and CR 24, 1977-1979 (Box 5)
  - CR 29-CR 31, undated (Box 5)
  - CR 35 and Texas H1N1 Isolates, 1975-1985 (Box 5)
  - Department of Epidemiology-Promotions and Appointments, 1995-1997 (Box 5)
  - Department of Epidemiology-Staff Photos, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Department of Epidemiology-Year's Activities, 1980-1981; 1984-1986; 1997-1999 (Box 5)
  - Flow Laboratories Inc., 1980-1988 (Box 5)
  - Francis E. Payne Memorial, 1980; 1982 (Box 5)
  - Graduate Student Record, 1953-1955 (Box 5)
  - Higashi, Gene Isao, 1991 (Box 5)
  - High Yield Reassortment (HYR), 1989-1990 (Box 5)
  - HL Cell Lines, 1978; 1990-2000 (Box 5)
  - Importation of Sera from Canada, 1993-1996 (Box 6)
  - Influenza B, 1979-1985 (Box 6)
  - Kaketsuken (Japan), undated; 1986-1996; 11 folders (Box 6)
  - Letters of Reference, undated; 1984-2000; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Medical Research Council (MRC) Common Cold Unit, 1970-1976 (Box 6)
  - Michigan Department of Public Health, 1968-1978 (Box 6)
  - Michigan Public Health Institute, 1995-1997 (Box 6)
  - National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID), 1978-1980; 1987-1989; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Office and Laboratory Space, 1992-1997 (Box 6)
  - Pasteur Merieux, undated; 1991-2000; 10 folders (Box 7)
  - Patents
    - Correspondence, 1976-2000 (Box 7)
    - Attenuated Respiratory Syncytial Virus (RSV)
      - Corrected International Published Application, 1999 (Box 7)
      - Final Published International Application, 1998 (Box 7)
      - PCT Submitted Documents, 1999 (Box 7)
      - Search Authority Results, 1997 (Box 7)
    - Attenuated RSV Vaccine Compositions (International Patent), 1993 (Box 7)
    - Cold-Adapted Influenza Virus (US Patent), 1993 (Box 8)
    - Mutant RSV Vaccines (European Patent), 1993 (Box 8)
    - Two-Step Immunization Procedure Against the Paramyxoviride Family of Viruses Using Attenuated Viral Strains and Subunit Protein Preparation (US Patent), 2000 (Box 8)
  - Polio Vaccine Stamp Ceremony, 1999 (Box 8)
  - Respiratory Syncytial Virus (RSV)-Strieter's Work, 1996-1997 (Box 8)
  - St. Jude Children's Research Hospital, 1989-1993 (Box 8)
  - Salk Laboratory Dedication, 1995-1996 (Box 8)
  - Sandoz Forschungsinstitut GmbH, undated; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Shaman Pharmaceuticals Inc., undated; 1991-1992 (Box 8)
  - U.S.S.R. Collaboration, 1983-1984; 1990 (Box 8)
  - University of Michigan Immunology Program Task Force, 1998 (Box 8)
  - University of Pittsburgh, 1988-1992 (Box 8)
  - Vaccine Trials, 1977-1984 (Box 8)
  - Vanderbilt Isolate, 1988-1989 (Box 8)
  - Wyeth-Ayerst Laboratories, 1991-1993 (Box 8)
- Publications, 1954-1999
  Publications, 1954-1999 comprises a nearly complete set of Maassab's professional publications and non-published professional writings, arranged chronologically.
  - 1954-1959
    - Alcune Caratteristiche dello Sviluppo del Virus della Polmonite nel Neonata (Sendai), 1954 (Box 8)
    - Growth Characteristics of Influenza Virus, Biochemical Differentiation of Stages of Development, 1954 (Box 8)
    - Growth Characteristics of Influenza Virus, Biochemical Differentiation of Stages of Development II, 1955 (Box 8)
    - Growth Characteristics of Influenza Virus Concerning the Binding of Virus by Host Cells, 1955 (Box 8)
    - Growth Characteristics of Polio Virus in HeLa Cells: Nucleic Acid Metabolism, 1957 (Box 8)
    - An Infectious Ribonucleic Acid Derived from Influenza Infected Cells, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Nucleic Acid Metabolism of Virus-Infected HeLa Cells, 1959 (Box 8)
    - The Propagation of Multiple Viruses in Chick Kidney Cells, 1959 (Box 8)
  - 1960-1969
    - Influenza Virus Pericarditis, 1962 (Box 8)
      (see also box 28)
    - Isolation in Tissue Culture of an Interfering Agent from Patients with Rubella, 1962 (Box 8)
    - Fluorescent Antibody Studies in Tissue Culture of Parainfluenza 3 Infection, 1962 (Box 8)
    - Further Studies on the Infectivity of Ribonucleic Acid Prepared from Influenza-Infected Cells, 1963 (Box 8)
    - Rubella Antibodies in Human Serum: Detection by the Indirect Fluorescent-Antibody Technique, 1964 (Box 8)
    - Influence of 5-Fluorodeoxyuridine on the Growth Characteristics of Rubella Virus, 1964 (Box 8)
    - Studies on the Antiviral Activity of Amantadine Hydrochloride, 1965 (Box 8)
    - Detection of Rubella Antibodies in Human Serum by the Indirect Fluorescent Antibody Technique, 1965 (Box 8)
    - Inner Component of Respiratory Syncytial Virus, 1965 (Box 8)
    - Rubella Synovitis in a One-Year-Old Patient, 1966 (Box 8)
    - Characteristics of Serially Propagated Monkey Kidney Cell Cultures with Persistent Rubella Infection, 1966 (Box 8)
    - Antiviral Activity of a-Methyl-1-Adamantane-Methylamine Hydrochloride, 1966 (Box 8)
    - Adaptation of Respiratory Synecytial (RS) Virus to Brain of Suckling Mice, 1966 (Box 8)
    - Sudden Deafness Associated with Adenovirus Infection, 1967 (Box 8)
    - An Immunofluorescent and Histopathological Study of Respiratory Syncytial (RS) Virus Encephalitis in Suckling Mice, 1967 (Box 8)
    - Plaque formation of Influenza Virus at 25ºC, 1968 (Box 8)
    - Laboratory and Clinical Characteristics of Attenuated Strains of Influenza Virus, 1969 (Box 8)
    - Biologic and Immunologic Characteristics of Cold-Adapted Influenza Virus, 1969 (Box 8)
    - Nucleo-cytoplasmic Studies in the Development of Influenza Virus in Mammalian Cells, 1969 (Box 8)
  - 1970-1974
    - Inhibition of a Cold Variant of Influenza Virus by Selected Chemicals, 1970 (Box 8)
    - Development of Variants of Influenza Virus, 1970 (Box 8)
    - Pilot Studies on Mono and Bivalent Live Attenuated Influenza Virus Vaccines, 1971 (Box 8)
    - A Comparative Study of Attenuated Influenza Viruses, 1971 (Box 8)
    - Live Influenza Vaccine Studies in Human Volunteers, 1972 (Box 8)
    - Characterization of Herpes Simplex Virus Types 1 and 2 Adapted to Growth at 25º C, 1973 (Box 8)
    - The Role of Viruses in Sudden Deafness, 1973 (Box 8)
    - Comparative Studies of Wild-Type and 'Cold Mutant' (Temperature Sensitive) Influenza Viruses: Polypeptide Synthesis by an Asian (H2N2) Strain and its Cold-Adapted Variant, 1973 (Box 8)
    - Influenza Neuramindase Antibody Patterns of Man, 1973 (Box 8)
    - Properties of Influenza Virus 'Cold' Recombinants, 1973 (Box 8)
    - Local Immunity to Influenza Virus in Chicken Tracheal Organ Cultures, 1974 (Box 8)
    - Infection by Influenza A Viruses of Tracheal Organ Cultures Derived from Homologous and Heterologous Hosts, 1974 (Box 8)
  - 1975-1979
    - Interaction of Listeria Monocytogenes and Influenza in an Animal Model, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Characteristics of a Live Avian Influenza Virus, 1976 (Box 8)
    - Principles of Influenza Virus 'Cold' Recombinants, 1976 (Box 8)
    - Protocol for a Study of the Clinical Reactivity and Immunogenicity of Two Cold-Adapted Recombinants of Influenza Viruses, 1976 (Box 8)
    - The Effect of Cyclic Nucleotides on Virus Infection, 1977 (Box 8)
    - Comparative Studies of Wild-Type and 'Cold Mutant' (Temperature Sensitive) Influenza Viruses: Genealogy of the Matrix (M) and Non-Structural (NS) Proteins in Recombinant Cold-Adapted H3N2 Viruses, 1977 (Box 8)
    - A Placebo-Controlled Dose-Response Study of the Reactogenicity and Immunogenicity of a Cold-Adapted Recombinant A/Victoria/3/75 (H3N2) Live Influenza Virus Candidate Vaccine in Healthy Volunteers, 1977 (Box 8)
    - Cold Adapted Variants of Influenza Virus A, I, 1977 (Box 8)
    - Cold Adapted Variants of Influenza Virus A, II, 1977 (Box 8)
    - Cold Adapted Variants of Influenza Virus A, III, circa 1977 (Box 8)
    - Cold Adapted Variants of Influenza Virus A, IV, circa 1977 (Box 8)
    - Cold Adapted Variants of Influenza Virus A, V, circa 1977 (Box 8)
    - Use of Influenza Vaccine in Non-High Risk Populations, 1977 (Box 8)
    - Pilot Studies on Recombinant Cold-Adapted Live Type A and B Influenza Virus Vaccines, 1977 (Box 8)
    - Biologic, Genetic and Biochemical Characterization of a Cold-Adapted Recombinant A/Victoria/3/75 Virus and Its Evaluation in Volunteers, 1977 (Box 8)
    - Biochemical Characteristics of Recombinant Viruses Derived at Sub-Optimal Temperatures: Evidence that ts Lesions Are Present in RNA Segments 1 and 3, and that RNA 1 Codes for the Virion Transcriptase Enzyme, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Biologic Characteristics of Influenza Virus Recombinants Derived at Suboptimal Temperatures, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Growth Characteristics of Influenza Virus Type C in Avian Hosts, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Comparative Studies of Wild-Type and Cold-Mutant (Temperature Sensitive) Influenza Viruses: Independent Segregation of Temperature-Sensitivity of Virus Replication from Temperature-Sensitivity of Virion Transcriptase Activity During Recombination of Mutant A/Ann Arbor/6/60 with Wild Type H3N2 Strains, 1979 (Box 9)
    - Comparative Studies of Wild-Type and Cold-Mutant (Temperature Sensitive) Influenza Viruses: Nonrandom Reassortment of Genes During Preparation of Live Virus Vaccine Candidates by Recombination at 25º Between Recent H3N2 and H1N1 Epidemic Strains and Cold-Adapted A/Ann Arbor/6/60, 1979 (Box 9)
    - Influenza Virus Infection of Newborn Rats: Virulence of Recombinant Strains Prepared from a Cold-Adapted, Attenuated Parent, 1979 (Box 9)
    - Effects of Cyclic Nucleotide on Coronavirus Replication (40516), 1979 (Box 9)
    - Comparative Studies of Wild-Type and Cold-Mutant (Temperature Sensitive) Influenza Viruses: Evaluation in Adult Seronegative Volunteers of A/Scotland/840/74 and A/Victoria/3/75 Cold-Adapted Recombinants Derived from the Cold-Adapted A/Ann Arbor/6/60 Strain, 1979 (Box 9)
  - 1980-1984
    - Genetic Approaches to Attenuation of Influenza A Viruses for Man, 1980 (Box 9)
    - Studies in Man with Cold-Recombinant Influenza Virus (H1N1) Live Vaccines, 1980 (Box 9)
    - Studies with a Cold-Recombinant A/Victoria/3/75 (H3N2) Virus, I: Biologic, Genetic, and Biochemical Characterization, 1980 (Box 9)
    - Evaluation of Influenza A/Hong Kong/123/77 (H1N1) ts-1A2 and Cold-Adapted Recombinant Viruses in Seronegative Adult Volunteers, 1980 (Box 9)
    - Ortho-and Paramyxoviruses in the Migratory Waterfowl of Michigan, 1981 (Box 9)
    - Ultrastructural Changes in Hepatocytes of a Potential Animal Model of Reye's Syndrome, 1981 (Box 9)
    - Evaluation of A/Alaska/6/77 (H3N2) Cold-Adapted Recombinant Viruses Derived from A/Ann Arbor/6/60 Cold-Adapted Donor Virus in Adult Seronegative Volunteers, 1981 (Box 9)
    - Characterization of the Temperature Sensitive Phenotype of the A/Ann Arbor/6/60 Cold-Adapted Virus and Its Recombinants, 1981 (Box 9)
    - Characterization of Influenza Virus 'Cold' Recombinants Deriyed at the Non-Permissive Temperature (38º), 1981 (Box 9)
    - Relative Efficacy of Embryonated Eggs and Cell Culture for Isolation of Contemporary Influenza, 1981 (Box 9)
    - Development of Cold-Adapted Recombinant Live, Attenuated Influenza A Vaccines in the U.S.A. and U.S.S.R., 1981 (Box 9)
    - Development of Cold Recombinants of Influenza Virus as Live Virus Vaccines, 1981 (Box 9)
    - Serologic Responses to Nonprevalent Influenza A Viruses During Intercyclic Periods, 1981 (Box 9)
    - Characterization of Recombinants Derived at Different Temperatures, 1981 (Box 9)
    - Ether Treatment of Type B Influenza Virus Antigen for the Hemagglutination Inhibition Test, 1981 (Box 9)
    - Evaluation of an Attenuated, Cold-Recombinant Influenza B Virus Vaccine, 1981 (Box 9)
    - Genetic and Biochemical Analysis of the A/Ann Arbor/6/60 Cold-Adapted Mutant, 1981 (Box 9)
    - Evaluation of an Attenuated, Cold-Recombinant Influenza B Virus Vaccine, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Infant Rat Model of Attenuation for Recombinant Influenza Viruses Prepared from Cold-Adapted Attenuated A/Ann Arbor/6/60, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Cold Adapted Recombinants of Influenza A Virus in MDCK Cells, I, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Interaction of Aspirin and Other Potential Etiologic Factors in an Animal Model of Rye Syndrome, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Evaluation of a Cold-Recombinant Influenza Virus Vaccine in Ferrets, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Influenza A Cold-Adapted Recombinant Vaccines in Young, Seronegative Children, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Serum Enzyme Alterations in Arginine-Deficient, Influenza-Infected Ferrets, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Prospects for Live, Attenuated Vaccines, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Characterization of a Nonvirulent Variant of Lymphocytic Choriomeningitis Virus, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Cold Adapted Reassortments of Influenza A Virus in MDCK Cells, II, 1983 (Box 9)
    - Alternations in Influenza Virus Pulmonary Pathology Induced by Diethyl Ether, Halothane, Enflurane, and Pentobarbital Anesthesia in Mice, 1983 (Box 9)
    - Structural and Morphometric Studies of Liver in a Ferret Model of Reye's Syndrome, 1983 (Box 9)
    - Characterization of an Influenza A Host Range Mutant, 1983 (Box 9)
    - Live Attenuated Cold-Adapted Influenza A Virus Induces Better Resistance than Inactivated Vaccine to Experimental Challenge with Wild-Type Virus, 1983 (Box 9)
      (unpublished)
  - 1984-1989
    - Analysis of an Influenza A Virus with a Deletion in the NS Segment, 1984 (Box 9)
    - Dose Response of Influenza A/Washington/897/80 (H3N2) Cold-Adapted Reassortant Virus in Adult Volunteers, 1984 (Box 9)
    - The Basis of Attenuation of Virulence of Influenza Virus for Man, 1984 (Box 9)
    - The Nonstructural Gene Segment of Influenza A Virus: Expression of NS1 Protein in Mammalian Cells; Analysis of a Deletion Mutant, 1984 (Box 9)
    - Attenuation of Wild-Type Human Influenza A Virus by Acquisition of the PA Polymerase and Matrix Protein Genes of Influenza A/Ann Arbor/6/60 Cold-Adapted Donor Virus, 1985 (Box 9)
    - Development of Cold-Adapted 'Master' Strains for Type-B Influenza Virus Vaccines, 1985 (Box 9)
    - Development and Characterization of Cold-Adapted Viruses for Use as Live Virus Vaccines, 1985 (Box 9)
    - Genes of Cold-Adapted B/Ann Arbor/1/66 Influenza Virus Determining Cold-Adaptation and Temperature Sensitivity, circa 1985 (Box 9)
    - The Acquisition of the RNA Segments 3 and 7 of the Influenza A/Ann Arbor/6/60 Cold-Adapted Donor Virus Attenuates Wild Type Influenza A Virus for Humans, 1985 (Box 9)
    - Prospects for Live Influenza Virus Vaccine for Man, 1985 (Box 9)
    - Cold-Adapted Reassortants of Influenza A Virus: Pathogenicity of A/Ann Arbor/6/60 x A/Alaska/6/77 Reassortant Viruses In Vivo and In Vitro, 1986 (Box 9)